Muhammad Aspan Yunandar, S.T.

Java Backend Developer



Date of Birth : Jakarta, 9 November 1996

Address : Baru Kemang Street Number 30 Tonjong, Tajur

Halang, Bogor Regency, West Java

Martial Status : Single
Religion : Moslem

Phone Number : 0895 8048 39800

Email : aspanyundar20@gmail.com

Github : <u>aspanyndr</u>

Website : linkedin.com/in/muhammad-aspan-yunandar-96311a1a3

I have skills in programming and developing applications especially on the web to develop backend. Recently I joined a technology company which helped me improve my knowledge of technology, especially with java using springboot and developing APIs with API Management like WSO2.

Also I'm experience using other middleware tools like Redhat Fuse, weblogic and Apache Tomcat. Apart from that, I am quite proficient in Cloud infrastructure (RHOSP) and Linux administration using Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL) and CentOS. And recently im also start learning public cloud like AWS and want to know more about other public cloud

Job Experience

PT Inovasi Informatika Indonesia, South Jakarta (Hybrid) | Fulltime

Cloud Consultant as Fulltime Employee, June 2023 - Mei 2024

- Manageservice RHOSP (Redhat Opensatck Platform) in Aplikasinusa Lintasarta as L1 Cloud Infrastructure
 - Setting and Tuning Monitoring Tools using Grafana with node exporter, push gateway and collectd in existing
 - Health check and Creating Alert witch customization script for existing Cluster
 - Create MOPs and apply Enhancements to add or improve features in existing clusters
 - Troubleshoot and support L1 ticketing
 - PM CM every month for all cluster

Middleware consultant as Fulltime Employee, october 2022 - Presents

- Learning about Redhat Middleware tools (3scale, fuse and jboss) and learning Openshift Container Platform
- Research API management using WSO2 API Management for POC and existing opty
- Preventive and Corrective Maintanace 3Scale Integrations, Redhat SSO at Pegadaian
- Preventive Maintanace 3Scale Integrations, Redhat SSO at HanaBank
- Creating SOP and Hardening Apache Tomcat

PT Prosigmaka Mandiri, Jakarta (Online) | Bootcamp

Technical Consultant Program as contract employee, June 2022 - september 2022

- Learning about frontend using React.js, css, html for developing application
- Learning about Java Fundamental and use java springboot for develop backend application
- Learning Basic linux and Docker

PT Telkom Indonesia, Divisi Digital Service - Bandung, West Java | Internship

- Making research on projects that related to the Internet of things (IoT)at Divisi Digital Service.
- Making Support for Testing on projects that are being worked on by the Company.
- Make a report from the result of research.

PT Telkom Indonesia, Plaza Telkom - Palembang, SouthSumatera | Internship

Student Internship as Fiber Optic Engineer, May 2017 to July 2017

- Assist in monitoring Fiber Optic cables in the South Sumatra area.
- Checking and Troubleshooting Hardware at Witel from South Sumatra

Education

Telkom University, Bandung, West Java (2015 to 2021)

Bachelor Degree - Electronics Engineering, GPA 2.80

- Research Assistant of Microprocessor and Interfacing Laboratory (UPCI) 2018.
- Member of Logistic Division in The Smart Home Seminar and Comprehensive Training (TESSERACT) 2018.
- Member of Consumption and Danus Division in Blue Techno Festival 2017.

SMAN 6 Jakarta, South Jakarta (2012 to 2015)

Natural Science

- Member of Jujitsu Mahakam and Rohani islam extracurricular
- Representive from SMA Negeri 6 Jakarta as Barisan Nusantara for NationalEducation Day 2013 in Ministry of Education and Culture

Course and Certificate

- Dicoding: Cloud Practitioner Essentials (Belajar Dasar AWS Cloud), Belajar Dasar Pemrograman JavaScript
- HackerRank: Java Basic 2023
- Prodemy: Junior Technical Consultant Fullstack Technology, 2022
- Coursera: Crash Course on Python, 2022
- Progate: Kursus SQL, 2020

Skills and Abilities

Linux

Redhat Enterprose Linux (RHEL), CentOS

Programming

Java (Springboot), javascript (React.js), Node.js, html, css, Python, Bash

Cloud

Redhat Openstack Platform, Amazon Web Service

DevOps

Openshift Container Platforn, Docker, Container

Middleware tools

WSO2 API Manager, Redhat 3Scale Integration, Redhat Fuse, Redhat Jboss, Keycloack Single sign on, Apache Tomcat, Oracle Weblogic

Foreign Language

English (Active